Ash Blue



ash@blueashes.com



linkedin.com/in/ashblue



312-344-3792



https://github.com/ashblue

Summary

Senior software engineer leading teams for 10+ years creating web applications. My career has brought me from San Francisco's startup scene to fortune 500s. I specialize in JavaScript full stack with CI/CD to help teams create cutting-edge solutions.

In addition to mentoring, maintaining open-source packages used by thousands, and organizing development Meetup events. I've co-authored HTML5 in Action under Manning Publications, writing on interactive media APIs. Some of my other specialties include React (hooks and context), Angular 2+, Node.js, component design systems, SOLID, and test automation.

Experience



Senior Developer

DrFirst, Inc.

Mar 2020 - Present (1 year 9 months +)

Application software development for a Telehealth chat and video solution. Think Slack for communicating with your doctor. Did architecture and coding for the app's video communication tool with Twilio's video API on top of Facebook's Create React App (hooks and context). Worked on the live chat tool with Google's Angular 7 - 12 and Material UI. Product team of roughly 20 people with 5 dedicated to the front-end code portion.

- Reduced post-release patches in the SDLC with Cypress E2E test automation and code coverage CI checks. Went from several patches every release to just a few a year
- Refactored large portions of the app into Atomic Design to create a data driven component system. Reduced app total line size over 50% and helped with faster rapid prototyping
- Reduced deployment risk by re-architecting the product's monolith (roughly 200k lines) into micro-front-end applications and custom NPM packages (20 30k lines each)

Principal Engineer

Havenly

Sep 2019 - Jan 2020 (5 months)

Principal full stack engineer working on the company's e-commerce pages with Next.js to implement SSR. Additional responsibilities included implementing sustainable coding practices, refactoring applications to enable testing, mentoring developers, and setting up initial architecture for apps. Tech stack heavily focused on React (hooks and context), Apollo Graph, MySQL, AWS, and full-stack Node.js.

- Implemented Next.js (a React SSR framework) to reduce page load times with Apollo Graph for the company's product pages
- Reduced production bugs with sustainable coding practices. Introduced Git Flow, unit testing, E2Es, and Semantic Release, which I trained team members on

- Ran retros to identify developer challenges and groomed tickets to help identify potential spikes. High communication with the business to help them move faster

buildit Senior Front End Engineer

buildit

Dec 2017 - Aug 2019 (1 year 9 months)

Full stack developer responsible for implementing test driven CI/CD solutions with a large focus on automation to replace pre-existing software. Large focus on API consumption, CLI tools, and front-end frameworks with SOLID principles. Primarily specializing in Angular 2+ CLI to rapidly build scalable MVPs with the ability to evolve based upon a long term road map.

- Established improved methods of rapid delivery with Git Flow, Swagger, NPM packages, and Semantic Release
- Helped implement 80%+ code coverage systems that increased speed of code delivery
- Created a custom style guide framework to overcome challenges in Pattern Lab and Fabricator for integration with SPAs

Senior Front End Developer

AUTOPAY

Nov 2015 - Mar 2017 (1 year 5 months)

Senior front-end responsible for organizing multiple members and coordinating with the back-end. Architected all Node.js environments and primary front-end consultant for all departments. Rewrote a large chunk of the company's legacy front-end into a modular format that rapidly sped up development. Also responsible for maintaining a large scale Ember.js and Angular 2 application.

Ash Blue Web Design Full Stack Developer

Ash Blue Web Design

Dec 2013 - Nov 2015 (2 years)

Contracting work on React, Angular, and Node.js projects for various companies in the bay area. In charge of development teams for companies such as Nvidia, Visa, and several other major clients. Staffed to give projects a clear development direction, provide consulting, code software, and communicate technical aspects of the project directly with the end-client.

Front End Developer

Tastemaker, Inc.

Mar 2013 - Nov 2013 (9 months)

Created a standardized CSS and JavaScript system that boosted page speed load times at least 40% while increasing front-end productivity. Reworked a large portion of the existing code base to utilize responsive layouts with SCSS and HTML5. Built several stand alone JavaScript apps such as a reusable front-end cropping tool, visual image editor, and form validation library.

Software Engineer

Fandom

Nov 2012 - Apr 2013 (6 months)

Creation of and maintaining a custom JavaScript framework for visual data representation. Developing a custom CSS framework for a responsive data dashboard. Full stack development with Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Apache, and Linux.



Co-Author of HTML5 in Action

Manning Publications Co.

2011 - 2013 (3 years)

Worked with 3 amazingly talented authors from the United States to the UK to craft HTML5 in Action. The book covers building several HTML5 apps with reusable components for everyday front-end development workflows. I particularly wrote the sections on HTML5's visual data APIs (Canvas, SVG, WebGL).



Front-end Developer

Nerderv

Dec 2011 - Oct 2012 (11 months)

Primarily responsible for keeping track of myself in a fast-paced environment. Development projects revolved around JavaScript applications and creating re-sizable front-end solutions for CMSs. President of the game development club. Responsible for training small teams on new technology while achieving project deadlines.

Ash Blue Web Design Owner (President)

Ash Blue Web Design

Jan 2007 - Jun 2011 (4 years 6 months)

CMS and design service. I founded the company and was responsible for all development and design. Was also responsible for all marketing efforts.

Education



MBI

Associate's degree, Youth Ministry 2008 - 2009



Lorain County Community College

Associates of Applied Business, Computer Science 2006 - 2007

Skills

JavaScript • Agile • React.js • Angular • Testing • Component Design • Full-Stack Development • Apollo GraphQL · Node.js · Express.js

Honors & Awards



3rd place - 2010 Chicago Startup Weekend - The Kauffman Foundation

Nov 2010

Worked with a small team to develop a full functioning eCommerce website in one weekend. Final

product focused on Women's beauty and care products.